Soldiers,
الجنود،
Why are you so slow to drink this wine?
لماذا أنت بطيء في شرب هذا النبيذ؟
Are you disrespecting me, the Imperial Envoy?
هل أنت لا تحترمني، المبعوث الإمبراطوري؟
Or are you disrespecting the Imperial Court?
أم أنك لا تحترم البلاط الإمبراطوري؟
Soldiers, listen to my command!
أيها الجنود، استمعوا إلى أوامري!
Yes, sir!
نعم سيدي!
We thank the Imperial Court for its grace.
نشكر البلاط الإمبراطوري على فضله.
We will not betray our country’s trust.
لن نخون ثقة وطننا
After drinking this wine,
بعد شرب هذا النبيذ،
tomorrow I will lead you into battle.
غدا سأقودك إلى المعركة.
Cheers!
هتافات!
Defend the nation! Kill the enemy!
دافع عن الوطن! اقتل العدو!
Second Brother!
الأخ الثاني!
Doggy, come here!
يا كلب، تعال هنا!
Don’t go! Find somewhere to hide.
لا تذهب! ابحث عن مكان للاختباء.
Go!
يذهب!
You should be grateful
يجب أن تكون شاكرا
you didn’t run into me when I was sick.
لم تصادفني عندما كنت مريضًا.
What are you trying to do?
ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟
Kill you all.
اقتلوكم جميعا.
Think carefully.
فكر جيدا.
We are with the Imperial Court.
نحن مع البلاط الإمبراطوري.
Imperial Court’s people.
شعب البلاط الإمبراطوري.
People from the Imperial Court deserve to die even more.
إن الناس من البلاط الإمبراطوري يستحقون الموت أكثر من ذلك.
We used to be with the Imperial Court too.
كنا مع البلاط الإمبراطوري أيضًا.
But look at us now.
ولكن انظر إلينا الآن.
What has the Imperial Court given us?
ماذا أعطتنا المحكمة الإمبراطورية؟
If you kill us,
إذا قتلتنا
will your lives get any better?
هل ستصبح حياتكم أفضل؟
If I kill you,
إذا قتلتك
the Imperial Court will just send more people.
سوف تقوم المحكمة الإمبراطورية بإرسال المزيد من الأشخاص.
The more they send, the more we kill.
كلما أرسلوا أكثر، كلما قتلنا أكثر.
There are plenty of empty stomachs here.
هناك الكثير من البطون الفارغة هنا.
You’re just the appetizer.
أنت مجرد المقبلات.
Sixth Brother, what's wrong?
أخي السادس ما المشكلة؟
Go.
يذهب.
Hurry, go!
اسرع اذهب!
Go!
يذهب!
Sixth Brother, wake up!
أخي السادس استيقظ!
Sixth Brother!
الأخ السادس!
Wake up!
استيقظ!
A few years ago,
منذ بضع سنوات،
it was the wine brought by the Imperial Envoy
كان هذا هو النبيذ الذي أحضره المبعوث الإمبراطوري
that made us all sick.
الذي جعلنا جميعا مرضى.
Most people died on the spot.
مات معظم الناس على الفور.
Later, we found out
وفي وقت لاحق، اكتشفنا
the court didn't send us to fight enemies,
لم ترسلنا المحكمة لمحاربة الأعداء،
but wanted to use our lives for a sacrifice.
لكننا أردنا أن نستخدم حياتنا للتضحية.
To restore a dragon vein at the border.
لاستعادة وريد التنين على الحدود.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
does a court like this
هل محكمة مثل هذه
deserve our loyalty?
هل يستحقون ولائنا؟
Yu Ming,
يو مينغ,
you need to decide if you serve the court
عليك أن تقرر ما إذا كنت تخدم المحكمة
or the people of Tang.
أو شعب تانغ.
The people see us as monsters,
الناس ينظرون إلينا كوحوش،
as beasts.
كالوحوش.
They even gave us a name,
حتى أنهم أعطونا اسمًا،
Sand Ghosts.
أشباح الرمال.
Humans and ghosts—
البشر والأشباح
how can they coexist?
كيف يمكنهم التعايش؟
Stop!
قف!
Qiu Wan, Qiu Wan!
تشيو وان، تشيو وان!
This is our own matter.
هذه مسألة خاصة بنا.
You go ahead.
اذهب للأمام.
Old Master,
السيد القديم،
this is military business.
هذه مسألة عسكرية.
Outsiders shouldn't interfere. Leave.
لا ينبغي للغرباء التدخل. ارحل.
Stop arguing.
توقف عن الجدال.
Jiang Sansheng from the kitchen battalion,
جيانغ سانشينغ من كتيبة المطبخ،
are you defying your superiors?
هل تتحدى رؤسائك؟
To military officers,
إلى الضباط العسكريين،
I treat orders as law.
أعامل الأوامر كالقانون.
But against beasts,
ولكن ضد الوحوش،
even if it costs my life,
حتى لو كلفني ذلك حياتي،
I won't let you do as you please.
لن أسمح لك بفعل ما تريد.
Princess,
أميرة،
the Princess hasn't become a Sand Ghost.
الأميرة لم تصبح شبحًا رمليًا.
She just wants to be with Guo Huai.
إنها تريد فقط أن تكون مع قوه هواي.
I lied to you.
لقد كذبت عليك.
Princess,
أميرة،
the court has ordered
وقد أمرت المحكمة
me to take you back.
أريد أن أعيدك.
You're still thinking about the court now?
هل مازلت تفكر في المحكمة الآن؟
They're fighting over there and we're still arguing here.
إنهم يتقاتلون هناك ونحن لا نزال نتجادل هنا.
Princess,
أميرة،
please come back with us.
من فضلك تعال معنا مرة أخرى.
Yu Ming, what have you done?
يو مينغ ماذا فعلت؟
So what?
وماذا في ذلك؟
We should've reached this point long ago.
كان ينبغي لنا أن نصل إلى هذه النقطة منذ زمن طويل.
Sleep.
ينام.
Old soldier,
جندي قديم،
Tang military regulations:
اللوائح العسكرية لتانغ:
infighting within the camp,
الاقتتال الداخلي داخل المخيم،
those who harm their comrades,
أولئك الذين يؤذون رفاقهم،
shall be executed on the spot.
سيتم تنفيذ الحكم على الفور.
To uphold military discipline.
للحفاظ على الانضباط العسكري.
Guo Huai,
قوه هواي,
do you still see us as soldiers?
هل لازلت ترانا جنودا؟
Since we drank that poisoned wine,
منذ أن شربنا ذلك النبيذ المسموم،
we haven't been.
لم نكن هناك.
We're beasts now,
نحن وحوش الآن
beasts who want to live for ourselves.
الوحوش التي تريد أن تعيش لأنفسها.
Elder Brother, Second Brother
الأخ الأكبر، الأخ الثاني
Elder Brother
الأخ الأكبر
Doggy
هزلي
Second Brother
الأخ الثاني
You and Elder Brother
أنت والأخ الأكبر
Stop fighting
اوقف القتال
I
أنا
I'm scared
انا خائف
Doggy
هزلي
All soldiers, listen up
يا جميع الجنود، استمعوا
We once swore an oath
لقد أقسمنا ذات مرة يمينًا
Not to fail our country
لا نخذل بلدنا
Not to fail our people
لا نخذل شعبنا
Fight for our nation
ناضل من أجل أمتنا
Die on the battlefield
الموت في ساحة المعركة
Now
الآن
If we cross the boundary between the living and the dead
إذا عبرنا الحدود بين الأحياء والأموات
We will end up harming the people
سوف ننتهي بإيذاء الناس
Is this what we should do?
هل هذا ما يجب علينا فعله؟
No, we shouldn't
لا، لا ينبغي لنا
Soldiers, don't forget our oath
أيها الجنود لا تنسوا قسمنا
Protect the nation and fight the enemy
حماية الوطن ومحاربة العدو
Now
الآن
We ourselves
نحن أنفسنا
have become the enemies of our own people
لقد أصبحوا أعداء لشعبنا
Brothers
الإخوة
For the last time
للمرة الأخيرة
I'll lead you to protect the nation and fight
سأقودك لحماية الأمة والقتال
Heaven and Earth
السماء والأرض
Blood seals our loyalty
الدم يختم ولاءنا
Heaven and Earth, blood seals our loyalty
السماء والأرض، الدم يختم ولاءنا
Guo Huai
قوه هواي
Wake up
استيقظ
Doggy
هزلي
Guo Huai
قوه هواي
Princess
أميرة
Everyone has their own mission
كل شخص لديه مهمته الخاصة
Lin Xiaoran
لين شياوران
Are you sure
هل أنت متأكد
that the dragon vein where soldiers are sacrificed
أن وريد التنين حيث يتم التضحية بالجنود
is actually changing the feng shui of the Tang royal family?
هل تغير فعليا فنغ شوي العائلة المالكة تانغ؟
Yes
نعم
From my observation
من ملاحظتي
They're not using human sacrifice to restore the dragon vein
إنهم لا يستخدمون التضحية البشرية لاستعادة وريد التنين
They're completely overturning and replacing it
إنهم يقلبونها ويستبدلونها بالكامل
It seems someone powerful in the court
يبدو أن هناك شخصًا قويًا في المحكمة
wants to use feng shui art to seize the throne
يريد استخدام فن فنغ شوي للاستيلاء على العرش
Sun, the magistrate of Fuping County, presented the Chapter of Ruling the Country
قدم صن، قاضي مقاطعة فوبينغ، فصل حكم البلاد
to a high-ranking official in the capital
إلى مسؤول رفيع المستوى في العاصمة
In Luoyang
في لويانغ
another high official is using Liuxiang Pavilion to control officials
مسؤول كبير آخر يستخدم جناح ليوشيانغ للسيطرة على المسؤولين
Now we've found someone is secretly overturning the Tang dragon vein
لقد وجدنا الآن شخصًا يقلب وريد تنين تانغ سرًا
Behind all these events
وراء كل هذه الأحداث
Could it all point to the same person?
هل يمكن أن يشير كل ذلك إلى نفس الشخص؟
It's obvious
إنه واضح
Let's go, we head to Chang'an right now
لنذهب، نتجه إلى تشانغآن الآن